You're listening to Lutheran.radio in Finnish.
“having shod your feet with the preparation of the gospel of peace” (Eph. 6:15)
What is it?
Christ says in John 14:27 about objective peace:
Peace I leave with you;
my peace I give unto you:
not as the world giveth, give I unto you.
Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be fearful. (John 14:27)
So it is something that Christ's own receive from Christ.
Jesus gives his own peace,
and that peace is something that does not depend on our own feelings,
but on what Christ does.
Of course, this is followed by a subjective filling of peace as well.
God's wrath has subsided.
God is with us.
Whatever happens, we are above defeat,
because the victor is with us.
The gospel is the gospel of peace.
Its content is the truth, which is also peace.
It brings with it peace from Christ's cross, which it promises, and does not demand anything from man.
And if there is something that demands,
then it is no longer the gospel of peace.
And no good will come from being ready to proclaim such a gospel.
So it is important that the gospel is true.
After that, a person can start thinking about how they are not ashamed of that gospel.
Or how they could be ready to tell about it
when asked
or when forced to testify.
The peace that comes from that gospel fills your heart with courage as well.
Being ready to proclaim the gospel of peace
protects you from a rocky terrain.
For all darkness flees from such courage of the heart.
And that courage of the heart, you receive again and again from the gospel of peace.
It is an entirely endless and inexhaustible source for it.
No darkness can take hold of that word,
and so you too have an endless, inexhaustible gospel of peace,
which fills your heart with readiness to proclaim,
and your feet with courage to walk forward.
Being therefore justified by faith,
let us have peace with God
through our Lord Jesus Christ. (Romans 5:1)
Scripture taken from The Holy Bible (1885), English Revised Version.